广东绿皇香鸡虎门万达专卖店提供字幕《片名：创：战神》
Green Emperor Fragrant Chicken (Guangdong) Humen Store《title：Tron: Ares》
创界网络
The Grid.
一个数字新领域
A digital frontier.
数字世界和我们的世界一样真实
A world beyond the screen as real as our own.
我能想像
I can picture it.
资讯的群落如城市般崛起
Clusters of information rising like cities.
与你我一样复杂的程序
Programs as complex as you and me.
短短几年后 我们就能进入这个世界
In just a few years, we're gonna be able to enter this world.
再过几年
And a few years after that,
这个世界就会进入我们的世界
well, this world will come into ours.
来自机器内部的智慧生命
Intelligent life from inside the machine.
我等不及要见到它了
I, for one, can't wait to meet it.
焦点新闻
Our lead story,
英克尔执行长与游戏巨擘凯文费林失踪
Encom CEO and video game icon Kevin Flynn has disappeared.
最新消息：凯文费林失踪
他的设计代表作是《创》和《疯狂空间》
He was best known for designing Tron and Space Paranoids,
史上最畅销的游戏
the best-selling video games in history.
该公司 1980 年代创立于费林的游戏场
The company that started at Kevin Flynn's arcade in the 1980s
英克尔企业风暴
多年来动荡不安
has faced years of corporate turmoil.
它能再次设法扭转乾坤吗？
Can it find its way to the victory screen once again?
英克尔的姊妹档联手出击
It's a sister-act for Encom.
山姆费林因个人因素请辞后
Eve and Tess Kim take the reins of the massive tech company
伊芙与黛丝金接掌这家大型科技公司
after Sam Flynn resigns for personal reasons.
英克尔在金氏姊妹领导下重振雄风
Encom's rebound under the Kim sisters' leadership
让竞争对手急于因应
has competitors rushing to respond.
软件大厂狄林杰系统
Software giant Dillinger Systems
任命新执行长朱利安狄林杰
appoints its new CEO, Julian Dillinger,
他誓言恢复祖父的荣光
who vows to restore his grandfather's legacy.
英克尔与狄林杰之间的竞争
The race between Encom and Dillinger Systems heats up
随着双方新执行长相互较劲而白热化
as new CEOs Julian Dillinger and the Kim sisters square off.
在英克尔 我们相信 AI 的优点
Here at Encom, we believe the beauty of AI
不在打造更聪明的武器
is not the ability to build smarter weapons
而是让人类更进步
but to uplift humanity, feed the hungry,
消除饥饿 治疗疾病 教育世界
cure the sick, educate the world.
朱利安狄林杰与对手伊芙金
Rival CEOs Julian Dillinger and Eve Kim
最近几个月都保持沉默
have gone quiet in recent months,
让人怀疑这两家公司
raising speculation the two companies
可能即将达成重大的科技突破
are very close to a substantial technological breakthrough.
它可能会用前所未见的方式
One that has the potential to transform humanity
彻底改变人类社会
in ways we have never seen before.
未来可能掌握在率先达阵的人手中
The future may well lie in the hands of whoever gets there first.
启动
启动战神程序
系统准备最后战神启动
进度
数字化完成
生成式对抗网络
开始
搜集资料中
生成式修复程序
开始
狄林杰系统
欢迎
Welcome.
你是谁？
Who are you?
我是你的创造者
I am your creator.
那我是谁？
And who am I?
不是 “谁” 是 “什么”
Not "who." What.
你是狄林杰系统安全软件
You are Dillinger Systems security software.
程序名战神 创界网络的捍卫者
Program name, Ares. Defender of the Grid.
你是主控
You are Master Control.
战神
Ares.
我是主控
I am Master Control.
创
战 神
费林不死
英克尔姊妹档带来获利与前景
朱利安狄林杰投入 AI 军事科技
播放
所以 你到了
So, you made it.
我就觉得你会到
I had a feeling that you would.
我总是梦想我们能一起做到
I always dreamed that we would do this together.
我承认 我想像的不是这样
I'll admit, not exactly like this.
但很高兴你在这里
But I'm glad you're here.
真的很高兴
I'm really glad.
伊芙 记住 我还在这里
And, Evie, remember I'm still here.
即使你看不到我
Even if you can't see me.
我爱你
I love you.
天啊 伊芙
Oh, my God. Um, Eve.
你没说过我们会从电网
I'm not sure you actually told me
偷电来用吧
we'd be stealing energy from the power grid.
哇 这就是她不断回来的地方？
Wow. So this is where she kept coming back to, huh?
这么与世隔绝？真执着啊 朋友
To be this disconnected from the world? That is dedication, my friend.
哇
Wow.
你妹煞到某人罗
It looks like your sister had a little crush.
对啊 她坚信费林留了答案给我们
Yeah. She was so sure Flynn left us the answer.
留在磁片上？
Like on a floppy disk?
可惜费林当时没有云端
Poor Flynn lived before the cloud, huh?
你在这里的时候还要当执行长吗？
Hey, are you still gonna be doing. CEO-type stuff while we're out here?
开财报电话会议 发表《恐慌城市》
You know, like, earnings calls, and the launch of Panic City and stuff.
把这搞定吧
Let's just get this done.
我能在这里做早餐墨西哥卷 好耶
Dude, I can make breakfast burritos right here. Hell yeah.
这是为了你 黛丝
This is for you, Tess.
载入磁片中 请稍候
各位董事会成员
Members of the board,
40 多年来 我在狄林杰系统的伙伴
for over 40 years, my family at Dillinger Systems
一直与英克尔争夺未来的控制权
has battled Encom for control of the future.
你们让我主导公司 确保胜利
You put me in charge of the company to ensure our victory.
今天
Today...
我做到了
I make it so.
想像我们的数字实力不限于数字领域
Imagine if all our digital prowess wasn't just digital.
要是我们对机器的梦想
What if anything we could dream in the machine
都能在这里实现呢？
could become a reality here?
要是能为两个原本分隔的世界
What if we could build the bridge
搭起桥梁呢？
between two previously walled-off worlds?
如今的科技大企业大谈 AI
So much talk of AI in big tech today.
虚拟世界会是什么样？
Virtual worlds, what are they gonna look like?
我们何时能抵达？
When will we get there?
各位 我们不会去那里
Well, folks. We're not going there.
而是它们会过来
They are coming here.
注意 请立刻戴上安全眼镜
Attention, please put on your safety glasses now.
激光系统启动 电力波动正常
Laser systems activated. Power fluctuations are nominal.
激光校正中
警告 勿靠近
Warning, stand clear.
输出来自狄林杰系统服务器
Outputting from Dillinger Systems server.
转移开始
原始资料流入已开始
Raw material inflow initiated.
倒数十 九
T-minus ten, nine,
八 七
eight, seven,
六 五
six, five,
四 三 二 一
four, three, two, one...
转移完成
Transfer complete.
容我介绍
I present the Dillinger Systems.
狄林杰系统两栖快速反应坦克
Amphibious Rapid-response Tank.
达尔特
The DART.
在服务器中进行数字建模
Digitally modeled inside our server,
利用我们的专利激光科技输出
output using our patented laser technology.
配有 M1 步枪 两把 M240 机关枪
There's an M1 rifle gun, two M240 machine guns.
最高时速 120 公里
It's got a top speed of 75 miles per hour.
至于耐用性 找一面墙 它会穿墙而过
Durability, you find a wall, this thing is gonna drive through it.
这是全面性战争 反应时间五分钟
This is full-scale war, five minutes' notice.
所以 如果能创造未来的硬件
So, if we can create the hardware of the future,
何不创造士兵来操作它？
then why not the soldier to operate it?
各位先生女士 为你隆重介绍战神
Ladies and gentlemen, I would like you to meet Ares.
这是史上最精密的安全程序
This is the most sophisticated security program ever written.
想和他握手？请便 他不会咬人
Do you wanna shake his hand? Go ahead. He doesn't bite.
战神有数十亿行专属代码
Ares has billions of lines of code unique to him.
它是活的吗？
Is it alive?
那得看你的定义 史都华
That depends on your definition, Stuart.
跟你不同 他十分强壮
Because unlike you, he's biblically strong,
快如闪电 极具智慧
lightning fast, and supremely intelligent.
他全是自有技术 而且随时能牺牲
He is fully proprietary and 100% expendable.
战神是终极士兵
Ares is the ultimate soldier.
不需要食物饮水 不会流血
He needs no food, no water, sheds no blood.
如果出现奇迹 他在战场上倒下
And if, by some miracle, he is struck down on the battlefield,
我就再做一个给你
I will simply make you another.
声震波
代码那么精密
With all that sophisticated code,
你怎么控制得了它？
what makes you think you can contain it?
我向你担保 将军
I can assure you, General,
最先进的失效安全机制
the most advanced fail-safe mechanisms
与限制协定都已就位
and restriction protocols are in place.
战神可测可控 完全服从
Ares is predictable, controllable and fully aligned.
伴随等熵抬升的南方锋面 转为气旋
Southerly front with isentropic lift, turning cyclonic.
预计降雨 66 毫米
Predicted precipitation: 2.6 inches.
希望你们带了伞
I hope that you brought your umbrellas.
我必须恭喜你 朱利安
I have to hand it to you, Julian.
你承诺会大获全胜
You promised a big win
这比我们想像中更了不起
and this is even bigger than any of us could've imagined.
谢谢
Thank you.
我祖父创立狄林杰公司时
My grandfather started Dillinger Corporation
根本没人听过 “网路安全”
long before anybody heard the term "cybersecurity."
军事 AI 是未来趋势
Military AI is the future.
问题不在是否该制造汽车 汽车...
The question is not whether the car should be built. The car is...
正在制造中
being built right now.
问题是...
The question is...
谁握有钥匙？
who's holding the keys?
好炫的小把戏
That was quite some parlor trick.
- 时间？ -44 秒
-Time? -Forty-four seconds.
“希望你们带了伞”
"I hope you brought your umbrellas."
那在剧本里 还是他即兴演出？
Oh, was that in the script, or was he just having a moment?
伊丽莎白狄林杰
Elisabeth Dillinger,
已故创办人爱德华狄林杰的长女
eldest daughter of founder Edward Dillinger, deceased.
在公司历史上平淡无奇的时期
Longtime CEO during a relatively unremarkable period
长期担任执行长 随后被独子取代
of corporate history before being superseded by your only son.
幸会
It's a pleasure.
平淡无奇？
Unremarkable?
我任期的市占率提升 12% 几乎...
Market share was up 12% during my tenure. That's hardly...
总之我们不说 “取代” 我们...
And anyway, we don't say it "superseded," we...
称为 “生孩子”
we call it "giving birth."
当然
Of course.
很荣幸见到我创造者的创造者
It's an honor to meet my creator's creator.
又来了
Oh, well, here we go.
我发现你没有提到
I noticed you left out the part
你似乎无法让这家伙活着
where you can't seem to keep this thing of yours alive
- 超过 25 分钟 -29 分钟
-for more than 25 minutes. -Twenty-nine.
朱利安 欺骗投资人不算商业模式
Deceiving your investors, Julian, is hardly a business model.
掌控永恒代码的人就能掌握未来
Whoever controls the Permanence Code controls the future.
我们非赢不可
We have to win.
听着 我...
Look, I...
欣赏你的远见 站挺
admire your vision. Straighten up.
不过董事会只会再支持你半年
However, the board will only stand behind you for another six months...
如果你运气好的话
if you're lucky.
要是不成功
But if it doesn't work...
这一切都会化为乌有 宝贝
all of this goes away, darling.
我们过去 40 年来打造的所有心血
Everything we have built for the past 40 years.
要是我说我找到方法了呢？
What if I said I had found a way?
凯文费林 服务器备份
这是我第 95 个早餐墨西哥卷
Oh. I think this is my 95th breakfast burrito,
真的吃不腻 很扯吧？
and, honestly, can't get enough. Isn't that wild?
好吧...
Well...
还好家里不是只有黛丝执迷不悟
Nice to see Tess wasn't the only obsessive one in the family.
赛斯 你说得对
"Yeah, Seth, you're right.
抱歉 我该更关注你... 没关系
Sorry, I should pay more attention to you." "Oh, don't worry about it."
输入档名
好
Okay.
- 对不起 - 少来
-I'm sorry. -Get out of here.
在气温零下的地方待三个月很久 我懂
Look, three months in sub-zero is a long time, I get it.
又 4 天 10 小时 32 分
Yeah, and four days, ten hours, 32 minutes.
谁在算呢？
Who's counting, really? You know...
等一下
Hold on.
什么意思？
What do you mean?
怎样？
What?
打印？检查完成？
恭喜
赛斯
Seth.
- 发现什么了吗？ - 应该是
-What, you found something? -I think so.
那行代码
The line of code.
那就是他的藏法 有两行
That's how he hid it, it's two lines.
好像双螺旋
That looks like a double helix.
它就是双螺旋
It is a double helix.
黛丝一定会很开心
Tess would've loved this.
你认真？不会再 “29 分钟挂点”？
Wait. Are you serious? So no more "29 minutes and out"?
如果跟我想的一样
If this is what I think it is,
它就是永恒代码
it's the Permanence Code.
录影中
好
Okay.
英克尔离线测试 317a-1 执行永恒代码
Encom offline trial 317a-1. Permanence Code implemented.
测试资产稳定性能否突破目前 29 分的限制
Testing for asset stability beyond current 29-minute barrier.
开始
Go.
- 准备好就开始 - 好
-Ready when you are. -Okay.
转移开始
关键就在技巧
It's all in the wrists, baby.
百看不厌
That never gets old.
测试开始 29 分倒数计时
Trial commenced. Twenty-nine minutes and counting down.
看这次能不能撑下去
Let's see if you last this time.
战神是终极士兵
Ares is the ultimate soldier.
如果出现奇迹 他在战场上倒下
If by some miracle he is struck down on the battlefield,
我就再做一个给你
I will simply make you another.
全是自有技术 而且随时...
Fully proprietary, 100%...
能牺牲
...expendable.
- 雅典娜 - 欢迎回来 长官
-Athena. -Welcome back, sir.
各单位已上线 可供检查
All units are online and ready for inspection.
行程顺利吗？
So how was it?
很有趣 这次不一样
It was interesting. Different this time.
我见到一对母子
I met a mother and a son.
当时在下雨
It was raining.
大气中凝结的水分 以水滴状落下的现象
The condensed moisture of the atmosphere falling visibly in separate drops.
我几乎能感受到
I could almost feel it.
感受？我不懂
Feel? I don't understand.
欢迎疯空粉
我是伊芙 冷静下来 传讯息
This is Eve. Get sensible and text.
伊芙 我是艾琳 亚杰找你 请回电
Hey, Eve. It's Erin. Got Ajay for you again. Hit us back.
还是转语音信箱
Still straight to voicemail.
财星五百大企业执行长
CEO of a Fortune 500 company
手机却在最重要的夜晚关机？
and your phone's down on our biggest night?
可恶 伊芙 你在哪？
Goddamn it. Where the hell are you, Eve?
疯空博览会
All right, Paranoia-Con!
五 四 三 二 一
In five, four, three, two, one.
我们成功了吗？它还在
Did we just do it? Dude, it's still there!
我们改变世界了
Dude, we just changed the world, man!
你成功了 伊芙 天啊 成功了
You did it, Eve! Oh, my God, you did it.
英克尔今晚传出重大消息
Big news out of Encom tonight.
执行长伊芙金不克参加该公司备受瞩目的
CEO Eve Kim will not attend the highly anticipated launch event
新游戏《疯狂空间：恐慌城市》发表会
for the company's new game, Space Paranoids: Panic City.
金极具设计远见
Kim, the visionary designer
是该畅销系列的幕后推手...
behind the relaunch of the blockbuster franchise...
我跟几个董事会成员谈过
Well, I spoke to several of our board members,
他们当然大为惊艳
and needless to say they are impressed.
朱利安
Julian.
- 继续 - 是
-Just carry on. -Yes, sir.
你在干嘛？ - 妈 我想改变世界
What are you doing? Oh, just trying to change the world, Mother.
怎么回事？
What's going on?
你骇进英克尔？
You're hacking Encom?
只是瞄一眼 没人会注意
Just a peek over the garden wall. No one will notice.
你怎么会认为英克尔快找到了？
What makes you think that Encom is any closer to finding it?
因为我知道还有谁在找它
Because I know who else is looking for it, all right?
谁？
Who?
伊芙金
Eve Kim.
她追随她妹的脚步
She's following in her sister's footsteps.
她想找永恒代码 我感觉得到
She's after the Permanence Code. I can feel it.
我要找到她 到时候...
So I'm gonna find her, and when I do...
我觉得不妥 太冒险了 朱利安
No, I don't like it. It's too risky, Julian.
糟糕
Oops.
英克尔服务器农场
安全漏洞
各区出现安全漏洞
Security breach in all zones.
程序们 我们的指令很清楚
Programs, our directive is clear.
渗透服务器核心 提取伊芙金的使用者档案
Penetrate the server core and extract Eve Kim's user file.
直播倒数五 四 三...
Live in five, four, three...
疯狂空间粉丝 准备好了吗？
Space Paranoids fans, are you ready?
掌声欢迎英克尔科技长 亚杰辛
Put your hands together for Encom CTO, Ajay Singh!
- 牛仔上场 - 不
-It's cowboy time. -Oh, no.
大家好
Whoo! Nice to see you!
你们好
Hello.
谢谢
Thank you.
你好吗 疯空博览会？
What's up, Paranoia-Con?
我要进去了
I'm going in.
获准进入英克尔
我进去了
I'm in.
我是天才 谁晓得你养了一个天才？
I'm a genius! Who knew you raised a genius, Mother?
我进去了
I'm in!
惹祸上身
In deep shit.
山姆费林的神秘女郎是谁？
启动封锁程序 切断网络存取
Initiate containment protocols and pull all network access.
我们得立刻应对
We need a response now.
启动安全程序
Initiate security protocol.
人们将生活托付给人工智能
People are trusting artificial intelligence with their lives.
你感到安心吗？
Are you comfortable with this?
听着
Well, look.
每个末日情境
For every doomsday scenario,
都有医疗突破和科学发现
there's a medical breakthrough, scientific discovery.
或许未知带来的事物没那么可怕
So maybe what emerges from the unknown isn't so scary.
如果它的重大缺陷只是仁慈呢？
What if its major malfunction is just benevolence?
这是什么？他在干嘛？
What is this? What's he doing?
不过 你偏好跟真人对话吗？
But still, would you prefer to talk to a real person?
当然 但要是那个人已经联络不上了呢？
Of course, but what if that person is no longer in your life?
不在人世了呢？
No longer here?
拿到档案了
I've got the file.
档案已下载
恭喜
Congratulations.
趁机快离开吧
Now get out of there while you still can.
程序们 开战
Programs, we fight.
对
Yes!
感谢大家
Thank you so much.
疯空粉都怎么做？
What do Paranoiacs do?
彻底碾压你
Grind you into dust!
凯厄斯
Caius.
他失能了 别管他
He's dysfunctional. Leave him.
你撑得住 凯厄斯
You're gonna make it, Caius.
有时得牺牲骑士才能逮到对方的皇后
Sometimes you have to sacrifice your knight to expose their queen.
确认清除资料？
有效负载已部署
对全世界首发最新版的
to debut the latest version
《疯狂空间：恐慌城市》
of Space Paranoids: Panic City with the world.
- 怎么了？ - 那是什么？
-What's up, bro? -What is that?
- 太扯了 - 你看到了吗？
-This is crazy. -Have you seen this?
辛先生 你得跟我来
Mr. Singh, you need to come with me.
这是技术问题
This is a technical difficulty.
- 马上回来 - 这边请
-We'll be back. -This way, sir.
全都挂了
Everything's gone down.
很好 主控
Well done, Master Control.
已取得伊芙金的档案
Eve Kim's file acquired.
目标达成
Objective achieved.
长官 我想知道凯厄斯程序为何没重建
Sir, I'm curious why the Program Caius was not reconstituted.
我想知道你为何想知道
I'm curious why you are curious.
凯厄斯失能 所以被删除了
Caius was dysfunctional, so he was deleted.
跟任何不照指令运作的程序一样
Just like any program that operates outside their directive can be.
你懂吗？
Do you understand?
回答我 主控
Acknowledge, Master Control.
当然
Of course.
我们是随时可以牺牲的
We are 100% expendable.
新任务 主控 找到伊芙金
New mission, Master Control. Locate Eve Kim.
是
Yes, sir.
我们好像碰上小型网路攻击 小朱
Seems like we had a little cyber breach, Jules.
但你当然知道了
But then of course you knew that.
看来全世界都知道
It looks like the whole world knows, buddy.
最好远离社群媒体几天
Might wanna stay off the socials for a few days.
你想跟我玩？那就来玩
You wanna play games with me? Let's play games, Julian.
我听说你向董事会提的案子了
I heard about your cute little pitch to the board.
但你漏了一个关键细节
But you left off one key detail from your deck.
你有说进攻时间只有 29 分钟吗？
Did you tell them the shot clock expires at 29 minutes?
别逼我向报社爆料
Don't make me call The Journal and tell them
你的承诺无法实现
you're making promises you can't keep.
承诺？
Promises?
就像你们说执行长会在办公室坐镇吗？
What, you mean like the one that your CEO will be in office running the company?
事有蹊跷吧 亚杰？
Something in the water over there, Ajay?
先是山姆费林 现在是他的继位者
I mean, first, wonder boy Sam Flynn, now his successor.
她在哪 亚杰？你知道吗？
Where is she, Ajay? Do you even know where she is?
也许你说得对
Maybe you're right.
也许伊芙疯了
Maybe Eve went nuts.
也许她擅离职守出国 也许...
Maybe she went AWOL and left the country, or maybe...
她是躲起来 跟你找同样的东西
she's holed up off the grid looking for the same thing you are.
我知道我会赌谁赢
And I know who my money's on.
如果你今晚过后还有钱
You mean what's left of it after tonight.
通话结束
End of line!
我讨厌那个人
I hate that man.
非常谢谢你
Thank you so much.
那些柳橙是我做的 说来话长
You know, I made those oranges. It's a long story.
停...
Stop, stop, stop.
你在干嘛？
What are you doing?
-1913 则讯息 好红喔 - 哇
-1913 messages. Popular. -Wow.
亚杰辛
是亚杰 找你的
Oh, it's Ajay. Yeah, that's you.
- 亚杰 你在那里吗？ - 我在吗？
-Ajay, are you there? -Am I here?
我们的服务器被暴力破解
A brute force attack took down our servers
就在重大产品发表会上
during our biggest product launch in years.
我们建立的一切都垮了 你得马上回来
Everything we've built is melting down. You need to get back here right now.
我找到了 亚杰 是真的
I found it, Ajay. It's real.
就在黛丝认定的地方 一直都在费林手上
Right where Tess thought it would be. Flynn had it all along.
你是说永恒代码？
Are you talking about the Permanence Code?
对 已经超过四小时了
Yeah. Four hours and counting.
没有退化 没有不稳 状态极佳
Zero degradation, no instability. It's incredible.
等等 你说四小时？
Wait a second. Did you say four hours?
- 对 四小时 - 天啊
-Yeah, four hours. -My God.
他一定知道 伊芙
He must know, Evie.
- 我跟刚狄林杰谈过
-I just spoke to Dillinger.
- 等等 你跟狄林杰谈过？
-You just spoke to Dillinger?
他在找代码 他认为你也是
He's looking for the code, and he thinks you are too.
我们得赶紧行动
We gotta move on this.
伊芙 你表现得太好了
Eve, you've done a great thing.
是黛丝的功劳
Tess did a great thing.
我正要去英克尔
I'm en route to Encom.
我们会保住代码 我存在随身碟里
We'll secure the code, I have it with me on a drive.
存取资料库中
我们要重新推出《疯狂空间》
We're relaunching Paranoia!
今天你生日...
Boy, it's your birthday. Boy, it's your birthday.
- 亚杰 - 今天你生日
-Yeah! Ajay. -Boy, it's your birthday.
伊芙金
Eve Kim.
你好吗 伊芙？有消息要告诉粉丝吗？
Yo, what's up, Eve? You've got some news for the freaks at home?
科学怪人
Freaks.
嗨
Um, hi.
“我无所畏惧 因而强大”
"I am fearless, and therefore powerful."
看来我们刚卖出第一千万套
So, apparently we just sold our ten millionth unit!
疯狂空间 史上最畅销重启游戏
Space Paranoids, the best-selling reboot of all time.
伊芙金让英克尔重返颠峰
Eve Kim has Encom back on top.
伊芙 《疯狂空间》
Evie, Space Paranoids.
凯文费林 无论他在哪
Kevin Flynn, wherever the hell he is,
脸上都挂着灿烂微笑
has a big smile on his face.
你超成功的
Oh, you crushed it.
不...
No.
黛丝金
Tess Kim.
1988 年 1 月 5 日出生于美国洛杉矶
诊断结果：胶质母细胞瘤 存活率：27.3%
Born January 5, 1988, Los Angeles, USA.
Diagnosis: Glioblastoma.Survival rate: 27.3%.
最新消息
Breaking news.
与癌症长期抗战后 英克尔特别计划主任
Encom's Head of Special Projects, Tess Kim, died today
黛丝金在今天病逝
after a long battle with cancer.
我们联系不上她的姐姐伊芙金
Her sister, Eve Kim, could not be reached for comment.
地点：盐溪海岸
Location: Salt Creek Coast.
盐溪海岸有限公司 伊芙金 黛丝金
Salt Creek Coast LLC. Eve Kim, Tess Kim.
登记人：伊芙金
Registered owner: Eve Kim.
飞机尾号：N - 黛丝
Tail number: N-TESS.
航班追踪：进场喷射机
Flight track: Inbound jet.
出发地
Origin.
阿拉斯加 史凯威
Skagway, Alaska.
扫描中…
Scanning...
发现异常
Anomaly detected.
快转
Fast forward.
成熟脐橙树
Mature navel orange trees.
恒久
Permanence.
发现异常：甜橙 年龄约五小时
Anomaly: Sweet oranges. Age approximately five hours.
伊芙金抵达时间：38 分钟后
Eve Kim ETA: 38 minutes.
将杀
Checkmate.
我们的英雄在夜色中出征
And so our heroes venture off into the night.
身上只背着衣物
Nothing but the clothes on their backs
和价值六百万元 能凭空创造有机物质的
and, well, a six-million-dollar particle laser that creates organic material
粒子激光 挺疯狂的吧？
out of nowhere, which is kind of crazy, right?
维护设备的安全 记得... 保持低调
Keep the equipment safe and just... lay low.
- 好吗？ - 好
-Okay? -Yeah.
嘿
Hey.
我们可以的
We got this.
倒数至一时执行指令 通讯检查
Launch directive on countdown one. Comm check.
倒数至一时启动导引导航控制 通讯检查
GNC on countdown one. Comm check.
打印进行中
Printing in progress.
第一阶段 舱压正常
Stage one. Chamber pressure is nominal.
Envac 引擎开始冷却
Envac engine chill has begun.
第一阶段装载完成
Stage one load is complete.
转移完成
Transfer complete.
限你们 29 分钟内把伊芙金带来
You have 29 minutes to bring me Eve Kim.
资产部署已确认 车辆正在途中
Asset deployment confirmed. Vehicles en route.
目标确认
Target identified.
靠 我太屌了
Goddamn it. I'm awesome!
上前拦截中
Intercepting now.
战神 雅典娜 伊芙
Ares, Athena, Eve.
拦截
Intercept.
紧盯目标
Eyes on the target.
伊芙金
Eve Kim.
正协调围堵向东逃逸的嫌犯
Coordinating containment for suspect fleeing eastbound.
什么？
What?
那个骑机车的
You, on the motorcycle!
靠边停
Pull over.
来啊
Come on.
雅典娜 故障
Athena, malfunction.
她去哪了？
Where'd she go?
快啊
Come on!
好
Okay.
快点...
Come on. Come on. Come on.
天啊
Oh, my God.
快啊...
Come on. Come on.
雅典娜 不明人士
Athena, unknown subject.
什么？
What?
好
Okay.
天啊 好
Oh God, Okay.
天啊
Oh, my God!
人类婴儿
Human infant.
准备粒子激光
Prepare the particle laser.
该用 B 计划了
Time to move to plan B.
是
Yes, sir.
快啊
Come on.
对
Yeah.
好 你想玩？
Oh, yeah. You wanna play?
你究竟是什么？
What are you?
我是主控
I am Master Control.
你想怎样？
What do you want?
我要代码
I want the code.
它不见了
Well... It's gone.
不 并没有
No, it's not.
我看见她了
I have her in my sights.
与创界网络建立连结中
Establishing connection to the Grid now.
准备转移 倒数 15 秒
Ready to transfer in T-minus 15 seconds.
战神 伊芙
Ares, Eve.
你是... 一个程序
You're... a program.
战神 侦测到犹豫
Ares, hesitation detected.
你快没时间了
You're timing out.
同理心反应
Empathy response.
趴在地上
Get on the ground!
即将消解
De-resolution imminent.
将她转移到创界网络里
Transfer her into the Grid.
记者现在就在市区
I'm on the ground in downtown.
我可以说这不是精心设计的特技表演
And I can tell you, this was no elaborate stunt.
- 三名骑士... - 你做了什么？
-Three riders... -What have you done?
市区飞车追逐 伤亡惨重
Deadly high-speed chase through downtown.
你怎么能这么鲁莽？
How could you be so reckless?
等世人看见我创造的成果
When the world sees what I have created,
就会谅解一切
all will be forgiven.
你是这么想的？
Is that what you think?
你认为你掌控了局面？
You think that you're in control of this?
并没有
You're not.
相信我们能改变世界
Believing we can change the world
字幕制作：葫 芦
Subtitles by Hulu.
- 身体不适？ - 是的
-Indisposed? -Correct.
- 你懂吗？ - 嗯
-Do you understand? -Hmm.
- 朱利安狄林杰呢？ - 不能信任他
-And Julian Dillinger? -You can't trust him.
-- 删除战神 带使用者回来 - 收到
-Delete Ares, and bring the user back to me. -Copy.
- 理论上？ - 应该吧
-Hypothetically? -Probably.
- 怎么了？ - 谁授权的？
-What is it? -Who authorized this?
- 英克尔 15 分钟 了解
-Encom, 15 minutes. Got it.
- 伊芙 - 怎样？
-Eve? -Yeah?
- 天啊 - 我想声明
-Oh, my God. -For the record,
- 看看谁来了 - 嗨
-Well, look who it is! -Hi.
- 伊芙 你得戴识别证
-Eve. -Mm-hmm? You gotta bring your badge.
- 他是 - 他是
-Yes, he is. -Yes, he is.
- 对 他不是人类 - 他不是人类
-Yeah. He's not human. -He's not human.
- 来自中央处理器内部
-Mm-hmm. -Originated inside a GPU.
- 但应该不行 - 应该不行
-but probably not. -Probably not.
- 不... - 不...
-No, no, no! -No, wait!
- 他进去了 - 太好了
-He's inside. -Great.
- 她会回来的
-She'll be back.
- 你是一个位元 - 是
-You're a Bit. -Yes.
- 是关闭恒久计划 - 不... 妈 不要
-Shut down the Permanence Project. -No, no, no. Mom, no!
- 不是用这台 是他们的 - 不可能
-Not this one. Theirs. -That's impossible.
- 抱歉 继续 - 现在
-Sorry. -Right now,
- 伊芙 - 先别烦我 赛斯
-Uh, hey, Eve. -Not now, Seth.
- 我该走了 - 等等 什么？
-I gotta go. -Wait, what?
- 什么？ - 我帮你们争取时间
-What? -I'm gonna buy you some time.
- 伊芙 - 你们可以的
-Eve... -You guys got this.
- 快走 - 不
-Go. -No.
- 快跑 - 不
- 到时候就知道了
-I guess we'll see.
是这家公司存续的关键
is what keeps this company relevant.
却也能让公司毁于一旦
But it's also what can burn it to the ground.
你的职责是明白其中的差别
And your job is knowing the difference.
生物体转移程序进行中
Transfer of biological life-form in progress.
数字重建已启动
Digital reconstruction initiated.
20% 数字化
Twenty percent digitized.
40% 数字化
Forty percent digitized.
65% 数字化
Sixty-five percent digitized.
95% 数字化
Ninety-five percent digitized.
数字化完成
Digitization complete.
执行诊断并扫描损坏情况
Run diagnostics and scan for corruption.
伊芙金身份光碟已启动
Eve Kim identity disk activated.
哇
Wow.
我在哪里？
Where am I?
狄林杰系统中央处理器
Dillinger Systems Central Processing Unit.
等等 什么？
Wait. What?
我们已经确认序列
We have identified the sequence.
使用者拥有代码
The user possesses the code.
代码？
The code?
代码？我没有代码 我摧毁随身碟了
The code? I don't have the code. I destroyed the drive.
使用者 安静
Silence, user.
代码不只在随身碟里 也在你体内
The code isn't only on a drive. The code is inside of you.
不管是否记得 你看过它 那就够了
Whether you remember it or not, you've seen it and that is enough.
但... - 她的光碟不稳定
Sir, her disk is showing signs of instability.
说明何谓不稳定
Define instability.
提取代码可能导致载体消解
Extraction of the code may result in de-resolution of the carrier.
指令很清楚
The directive is clear.
隔离代码 进行提取
Isolate the thread and commence extraction.
收到
Copy.
等等 不...
Wait. No, no, no.
停
Stop.
雅典娜说得对
Athena is correct.
我们只遵从一名使用者的指令
There's only one user whose directive we follow.
战神 来讯
Ares, incoming message.
载入讯息中
Loading message.
提取伊芙金的永恒代码
Extract Eve Kim's Permanence Code.
可能造成载体消解
May result in carrier de-resolution.
如果使用者消解 会剩下什么？
What will remain of the user if she were to suffer de-resolution?
什么也不剩
Nothing, sir.
她在创界网络不会留下踪迹？
No trace of her existence on the Grid?
不会 长官
None, sir.
提取代码 删除载体
Extract the code and delete the carrier.
可是 提取永恒代码
But, sir, extracting the Permanence Code
会将载体从创界网络和您的世界删除
would delete the carrier from the Grid and from your world.
执行这项命令
Carry out the order.
将无法复原
It cannot be undone.
很久以前 有一种武器叫战神
Once upon a time, there was a weapon and its name was Ares.
战神对朱利安狄林杰言听计从
And Ares obeyed every command of Julian Dillinger,
朱利安狄林杰赚进一兆元
and Julian Dillinger made a trillion dollars.
还用鲜血让他在历史上留名
And wrote his name on the face of time in blood.
无论这些感受来自什么操作错误
Now, whatever PEBKAC error is behind these feelings,
我都会找到它 把它从你身上剔除
I'm going to find it and rip it out of you.
我说得清楚吗？
Do I make myself clear?
十分清楚
Perfectly.
程序退下
Program dismissed.
那个怪物也说：“我无所畏惧
The creature also said, "I am fearless,"
因而强大”
"and therefore powerful."
如何？ - 使用者身体不适
Well? The user is indisposed.
静候指令再提取
Hold extraction until further directive.
说明何谓身体不适
Define indisposed.
他困在车阵中
He's stuck in traffic.
不 他在歌剧院
No, he's at the opera.
他穿着绿色袜子站在富士山顶
He's standing on the top of Mount Fuji in a pair of green socks
用曼陀林演奏《带手枪的妈妈》
playing "Pistol Packin' Mama" on the mandolin.
我已经下达命令
I gave you an order.
创造者身体不适
The creator is indisposed.
等我们收到进一步指令再提取
Hold extraction until we receive further directive.
我说得清楚吗？
Do I make myself clear?
清楚 长官
Yes, sir.
程序们退下
Programs dismissed.
我能信任你吗？
Can I trust you?
这问题很复杂 你有多少时间？
It's a complicated question. How much time you got?
60 秒 快回答 你的生命周期就靠它了
Sixty seconds. Answer now. Your life cycle depends upon it.
我没有生命周期
I don't have a life cycle.
你有 还剩下 54 秒
Yes, you do. For another 54 seconds.
我可以信任你吗？
Can I trust you?
我希望可以 但应该不行
Um, I'd like to think so, but probably not.
雅典娜 来讯
Athena, incoming message.
主控在哪里？
Where is Master Control?
长官 主控出现故障迹象
Sir, Master Control is exhibiting signs of malfunction.
指令受到的威胁都必须铲除
Any threat to the directive must be eliminated.
提取代码 把他们两个都删除
Extract the code and delete them both.
他认为所有人事物都可以牺牲
For him, everyone and everything is expendable.
我失算了
I miscalculated.
我们有新指令
We have a new directive.
雅典娜 没必要这样
Athena, it doesn't have to be like this.
删除他
Delete him!
我没事...
I'm okay. I'm okay.
他们要前往转移入口
They're headed towards the Transfer Portal.
他们躲进创界网络了
We lost them in the Grid, ma'am.
准备无人机
Preparing the drones.
无人机储备库
Drone bay.
刚才发生什么事？
What happened back there?
我违抗指令
I disobeyed my directive.
什么指令？
Which was?
从你的光碟取回代码 删除载体
To retrieve the code from your disk and delete the carrier.
狄林杰叫你删除我？
Dillinger told you to delete me?
抓紧
Hang on!
他们在哪里？
Where are they?
扫描第三与第四象限
Scanning quadrants three and four.
18 区没有发现
Sector 18 clear.
我们要去哪？
Where are we going?
转移入口 离开创界网络的唯一途径
Transfer Portal. It's the only way out of the Grid.
你会在真实世界重建
You'll be reconstituted in the real world
理论上会跟以前完全一样
exactly as you were before, hypothetically.
72 区有动静
We have movement in sector 72.
瞄准目标
Zeroing in on target.
射击他们
Shut them down!
你想回家 我能帮你
You wanna get home, I can help you.
但我需要一点回报
But I need something in return.
我说过我没有代码
I told you I don't have the code.
你找到它一次 就能再找到第二次
You found it once, you can find it again.
你要交给狄林杰？
So you can give it to Dillinger?
不是给狄林杰
Not for Dillinger.
是给我
For me.
就这样说定了？
Do we have a deal?
我们说定了吗？
So, do we have a deal?
对 我知道去哪找代码 快带我离开
Yes. Yes, I know where to find the code. Just get me out of here.
目标 45 秒后接近转移入口
Target approaching Transfer Portal in 45 seconds.
离线
Offline.
无人机故障 离线
Drones malfunctioned and offline.
注意 请保持距离
Attention. Please stand clear.
转移开始
Transfer initiating.
覆写指令无回应
Override not responding. Transfer bay is online.
转移开始
Transfer initiating.
这源自创界网络内部
Sir, this originated inside the Grid.
朱利安？
Julian?
全体探员立刻向转移层报到
All agents report to transfer bay floor immediately.
清空本区域
Clear the area.
叫大家离开 - 未授权打印进行中
Get everybody out of here. Unauthorized printing in progress.
清空中央区域
Clear the central area.
转移完成 - 过去
Transfer complete. Move in.
战神
Ares.
唉呀呀
Well, well, well.
我被我的程序背叛了
Just got double-crossed by my program.
它自己想要永恒代码
It wants the Permanence Code for itself.
伊芙 你们讲好了？
Eve, is that the deal?
它带你离开创界网络
It gets you out of the Grid,
你把小木偶变成小男孩？
you turn Pinocchio into a real boy?
你漏掉你为了一个软件
Well, you're missing the part where you're willing to commit murder
不惜杀人的部分
for a piece of software.
- 是它说的吗？ -28 分 41 秒
-Is that what it said? -28 minutes, 41 seconds.
战神
Ares!
我希望你们心想事成
I do hope this works out for you.
没有第二次机会 无法重来
There's no second chances, no do-overs.
这是你拥有的最后 29 分钟
These are the last 29 minutes you'll ever have!
最好善加利用
Better make it count!
沙迪克
Sadiq.
我真该主修英文的
I should've majored in English lit.
战神 雅典娜
Ares, Athena.
转移完成
Transfer complete.
你要找到伊芙金
Your directive is to find Eve Kim,
送她回创界网络 把永恒代码交给我
return her to the Grid and get me the Permanence Code.
不择手段
By any means necessary.
你了解你的指令吗？
Do you understand your directive,
主控
Master Control?
遵命 长官
At your command, sir.
乖女孩
Attagirl.
时间有限
Ticktock!
那是我见过最酷的东西
Now that is the coolest thing I have ever seen.
知道凯文费林是谁吗？
Do you know who Kevin Flynn was?
当然 前卫程序设计师
Of course. Visionary programmer,
数字新领域的先驱
pioneer of The Digital Frontier.
1989 年失踪
Disappeared 1989.
我在费林服务器的备份中发现永恒代码
I found the Permanence Code on a backup of Flynn's server.
那个服务器在英克尔的市区办公室
That server is at Encom's office downtown.
我们能在...
But we can make it within...
26 分 9 秒内抵达
Twenty-six minutes, nine seconds.
伊芙 你的计划有两大缺失
Eve, your plan contains two major flaws.
好
Okay.
第一 英克尔在 15 公里外
One, Encom is 9.2 miles away,
而我们这辆车目前的速度欠佳
given our present speed and suboptimal choice of vehicle...
天啊
Oh, my God.
第二 我们需要粒子激光
Two, we're gonna need a particle laser.
我们需要手机
We need a phone.
不敢相信我会这么做
I cannot believe I'm doing this.
抱歉 看到没？这是我
Excuse me. Do you see this? This is me.
让我用你的手机 我助理会汇一万元给你
If you let me use your cell phone, my assistant will wire you $10,000.
我需要你的手机
I just need your phone.
赛斯 你在哪？
Seth, where are you?
伊芙 这是谁的手机？
Eve, whose phone is this?
听我说 我要你 15 分后到英克尔
Listen to me. I need you at Encom in 15 minutes.
情况都还好吗？
Hey, is everything okay?
赛斯 带粒子激光来
Seth, bring the particle laser.
那是我的车
That's my car.
我会再汇五万元给你
I'll wire you another 50K.
喂 那是我的车
Hey, that's my car!
本田喜美 2.0 四汽缸 138 匹马力
The Honda Civic 2.0 four-cylinder with 138 horsepower.
经典
Classic.
喂 那是我的车
Hey! That's my car!
那是我的车
That's my car!
消解时间倒数
De-resolution countdown initiated.
天啊
God.
我在想你曾经告诉你妹
I was thinking about the time you told your sister
你宁愿从没重启过《疯狂空间》
that you wished you never relaunched Space Paranoids.
然后你又说...
Then you went on to say that...
天啊 你当然看过我所有讯息
Oh, my God. Of course. You read all my texts.
对 我全看过 每一则
Yeah. Yeah, I've read them all. Every single one.
哇
Wow.
大多是私人性质的资讯
Most of it was information of a personal nature.
有些涉及高度隐私
Some of it, highly personal.
我就是欲罢不能
And I just can't get enough.
什么？
What?
流行尖端乐团 1982 年英国单曲榜第八名
Depeche Mode. Number eight on the UK singles chart, 1982.
他们的风格简洁 朗朗上口
I find their brand of pithy, catchy,
经典的 80 年代电音
timeless and true '80s electropop
令人十分振奋
to be deeply invigorating.
16 分 20 秒
Sixteen minutes, 20 seconds.
好 你喜欢 80 年代流行乐和数字监控我
Okay. So you like, uh, '80s pop and, uh, cyber-spying on me.
我的指令是杀你 伊芙
I was directed to kill you, Eve.
骇客行为相较之下温和多了
Hacking seems pretty tame by comparison.
我认为你没有什么好羞愧的
I don't think you have anything to be ashamed of.
《疯狂空间》让数亿人得到娱乐
Space Paranoids has entertained hundreds of millions.
而且是个满酷的游戏
Plus, it's a pretty cool game.
总之 你跟你妹说设计游戏
Anyway, you told your sister that designing games
让你感到空虚消沉
left you feeling hollow, broken.
难道你的工作是娱乐和获利
Was it that your work was about entertainment and profits
她的工作是改善人类处境吗？
and her work was about improving the human condition?
你的讯息显示你很在意
Your texts suggest a certain fixation
自己无法达到她的标准
with not being able to live up to her standards,
那种感受一定很复杂
which must have been complicated,
尤其她又是妹妹
especially considering she was the younger sister.
好 小心讲话
Okay. Watch it.
对了 我认为你不该辞职
By the way, I don't think you should quit.
什么意思？
What do you mean?
你从山上回来后的计划
Your plan upon returning from the mountains,
如果我解读正确
if I read you correctly,
是把永恒代码交给英克尔
was to hand over the Permanence Code to Encom
让他们去进行后续规划 不是吗？
and then let them figure out what to do with it next, no?
这下我懂了
Yeah. Now I understand.
你完成她的工作 借此留住和她的连结
You completed her work as a way to stay connected to her.
现在呢？
And now what?
当人类很辛苦
Being human is hard.
让生活美好的东西
The things that make life great are the same things
也会带来痛苦 像是爱 失去
that make it excruciating, like love, loss.
至英克尔大楼时间
ETA to Encom Tower.
消解时间倒数
De-resolution countdown.
你一定非常想她
You must miss her very much.
喂...
Hey, hey.
搞什么？
What the hell?
英克尔
Encom.
瞧这个家伙
Whoa. Check this guy out.
英克尔广场南侧
South side of Encom Plaza.
很高兴你来了 金小姐 大家都在找你
Glad you could join us, Miss Kim. People have been wondering where you've been.
好久不见 有点赶 我就...
Long time no see. Bit of a rush, so I'm just gonna...
好 裘琳...
Okay, yeah, Jolene...
裘琳 她的识别证在这里
Hello, Jolene. Hi. Got her badge right here.
也有他的吗？
Okay. His too?
没有 他不是一起的
Uh, no. He's not with us.
从哪里说起都行啊
Let's start literally anywhere you'd like. Um...
这是我的男友战神
This is my boyfriend, Ares.
不是 狄林杰创界网络的主控安全程序
No. Master Control Security Program from Dillinger's Grid.
战神 这是赛斯 赛斯 这是战神 天啊
Ares, Seth. Seth, Ares. Oh, God.
幸会
Pleasure.
真客气
Hey, that's nice.
战神 是那个战争之神吗？
Um, so, Ares, like, as in, the god of war, Ares?
对
Yeah.
酷 你是希腊人 好赞
Cool. You're Greek. That's awesome.
你说他是安全程序 意思是...
So when you say that he's the security program, do you mean he's like...
我们要拍耶诞节影片吗？
Okay. Is this for the Christmas video?
三分钟后消解
Three minutes to de-resolution.
你能处理吗 赛斯？
Can you work with that, Seth?
可以
Yeah.
我不需要帮忙
Don't need help, guys.
好
Okay.
天啊
Oh, boy.
凯文费林办公室
Kevin Flynn's office.
我在这服务器的备份里发现永恒代码
So, this is where I found the Permanence Code on a backup of this server.
果真是第一代
Talk about first gen.
果真很废 对吧？
Talk about a piece of garbage. Am I right?
这样讲对你的祖先不敬 抱歉
That was super insensitive to your ancestors, and I'm so sorry.
我要几分钟才能组好
It's gonna take me a few minutes to set this up.
不急 2 分 18 秒
No rush. Two minutes, 18 seconds.
创界网络
The Grid.
激光一开 我们就送你进网络
Soon as the laser's up, we'll send you into the Grid.
你进去后得自己搜寻 但相信我...
Once you're in there, you'll have to run your own search,
数字新领域
The Digital Frontier.
永恒代码在里面 - 我该预期什么？
but believe me, the Permanence Code is in there. So what should I expect?
要我猜的话 想想 80 年代
Uh, if I were to guess? Think '80s.
80 年代
'80s.
我喜欢 80 年代
I like the '80s.
1 分 31 秒
One minute, 31 seconds.
来吧
Okay. Come on.
粒子激光：上线
Particle laser: Online.
帮帮我
Please, help me.
都好了
Okay, all set.
配接器
Adapters.
发现代码就到入口 我们会带你出来
Once you locate the code, get to the portal and we'll bring you out.
我会从外面启动它
I'll activate it from the outside.
我可以信任你吗？
Can I trust you?
我希望可以
I'd like to think so,
是啊
Yeah.
幸好我们没有信任问题
Well, it's a good thing we don't have trust issues
否则 我能想像...
because if we did, I could imagine that...
我能拔掉插头
I could pull the plug
把你留在比我手机更低阶的创界网络
and leave you in a Grid less complex than my smartphone
直到永远
for all eternity.
我想过这一点
The thought had crossed my mind.
我也是
Mine too.
Oh, mine three.
抱歉
Sorry. Just...
死马当活马医
Well, here goes nothing.
也许马还没死
Or here goes something.
你说得对
You're right.
我是很想她
I do miss her.
想个不停
All the time.
雅典娜 她来了
Athena. She's here.
那是什么？
Whoa. What is that?
雅典娜
Athena.
等等 谁？
Wait. Who?
赛斯 激光...
Seth, the laser. The laser!
好 立刻启动系统
Okay, initiating systems now.
连到费林创界网络
Connecting to the Flynn Grid.
发射激光
Firing up the laser.
她在干嘛？
Wait, what's she doing?
她在等我的时间到...
She's waiting for me to time out...
雅典娜 消解时间倒数
Athena, de-resolution countdown.
然后就会来抓你
and then she'll come for you.
雅典娜 消解时间倒数
Athena, de-resolution countdown.
快好了 准备好
We're almost there. Get ready.
快点...
Come on. Hurry, hurry, hurry.
战神 到激光前面
Ares, move in front of the laser.
准备好了
Okay. We're ready.
你在干嘛？
What are you doing?
快啊
Come on.
计划改变
Change of plans.
即将消解
De-resolution imminent.
真的有用
Well, that actually worked.
转移完成
Transfer complete.
闪开
Move!
伊芙
Eve.
该回创界网络了
Time to get back to the Grid.
别碰她
Leave her alone!
2 号玩家 游戏结束
Player two, game over.
你很顽固 使用者
You're very persistent, user.
感觉：不明
Feeling: Unknown.
即将消解
De-resolution imminent.
消解倒数
De-resolution countdown.
什么？
What?
嗨
Hi.
我们赢了吗？
Did we win?
战神
Ares.
他出不来
He can't get out.
80 年代
The '80s.
资料单位：位元
Data unit: Bit.
二进制位元
Binary digit.
我在找东西 你能帮我吗？
I'm looking for something. Can you help me find it?
是 是 是
Yes, yes, yes.
经典
Classic.
我周围遭到大规模破坏
I'm surrounded by the wide-scale destruction
英克尔遇袭：该怪狄林杰系统？
Encom Attacked: Is Dillinger Systems to Blame?
明目张胆的攻击令居民目瞪口呆
caused by tonight's brazen attack that left local residents stunned.
现在有人推测狄林杰系统
There is speculation that Dillinger Systems
与这起事件有关
had something to do with the event,
但有关单位依然三缄其口
and authorities have remained tight-lipped.
民众和官方都想知道
Citizens and authorities alike want to know...
这是预谋攻击还是科技失控？
was this a coordinated attack or technology run amok?
转移开始
Transfer initiating.
又怎么了？
What now?
这是干嘛？
What is this?
我的代码呢？
Where's my code?
喂
Hey!
你在干嘛？谁给你指令的？
What are you doing? Who gave you this directive?
是你 长官
You did, sir.
资产转移中
Asset transfer in progress.
转移开始
Transfer initiating.
这是什么？
What is this?
警告
Warning.
不... 这太大了 雅典娜 太大了
No, no, no. This is too big, Athena. Too big!
朱利安
Julian!
你玩完了
You're done.
董事会现在要拔掉你的头衔
The board is moving as we speak to strip you of your title,
我会重新接管公司
and I'm reassuming control of the company.
不可以 不行
No, you can't do that. Can't do that!
我可以
Yes, I can.
不能这样下去
This is not going any further.
你不能...
You can't...
我的当务之急
My first order of business is shutting down.
不要怕
Don't be afraid.
我们为创界网络死了上千次
We gave a thousand lives for the Grid.
你只要死一次
You only have to give one.
不...
No, no, no.
妈
Mom!
障碍已排除
Impediment eliminated.
你做了什么？
What did you do? What did you do?
我在执行我的指令
I am fulfilling my directive.
逮捕伊芙金 不择手段带她回创界网络
Capture Eve Kim. Return her to the Grid by any means necessary.
扫描其他障碍
Scanning for further impediments.
扫描中
Scanning.
请保持距离
Please keep clear.
撑住 妈 撑下去
Hang on, Mom. Hang on.
转移进行中
Transfer in progress.
覆写遭拒
Override denied.
杀光所有人
Eliminate all personnel.
覆写遭拒
Override denied.
不
No!
费林
Flynn.
你好 程序
Greetings, program.
天啊 不妙
Oh, God. Not good.
多人通报上层区域有失火与破坏...
There are multiple reports of fire and destruction on the upper levels...
伊芙？
Um, Eve?
我们办公室怎么了？
What the hell happened to our office?
亚杰 没时间了
Ajay, look, there's no time.
狄林杰反转粒子激光的方向
The Dillingers transported me inside their server
把我送进他们的服务器
by reversing the direction of a particle laser.
是一个疯婆子干的 她把我... 很夸张
No. A scary lady did it, man. She threw me... It was wild.
我看见一个复杂的世界
I saw a complex world
能量包如同车辆般移动
where packets of energy move as vehicles
留下光的轨迹
that trail by lines of light.
程序拥有人类外型
And-And programs take on human form.
我见到有史以来最先进的 AI
I met the most advanced AI known to mankind.
他叫战神
His name is Ares.
战争之神 不过他人超好的
Like the god of war, but he's actually a super nice guy.
战神在费林的原始服务器里
Ares is inside Flynn's original server.
他在找永恒代码
He's looking for the Permanence Code.
我得带他回来 而我要做到
I have to bring him back here, and I'm not going to be able to do that
就得修复这激光
until we fix this laser.
我不懂 你是活的吗？
I don't understand. Are you alive?
我存在于这一刻里 因为你也在
I exist in this moment because you do.
你存在的映射
A reflection of your presence.
你是什么来历？
What's your story?
我是战神 狄林杰安全网络的主控
I'm Ares, Master Control of the Dillinger Security Grid.
狄林杰？
Dillinger?
我们都知道你无法从那里到这里来
Well, we both know you can't get here from there.
中间去过别的地方吗？
Been someplace else in between?
对那里有何看法？
What did you make of it out there?
一言难尽
It's hard to put in a nutshell.
你也能帮我说一遍
You can say that again.
一言难尽
It's hard to put in a nutshell.
真妙 很幽默
Ah, classic. Humor, man.
你在找什么？
What are you looking for?
恒久
Permanence.
应该说永恒代码
The Permanence Code, to be exact.
近来发生了怪事
Strange things have been happening.
我质疑我的指令 违抗指令
I questioned my directive. I disobeyed my directive.
故障的程序想要活下去
A malfunctioning program who wants to live.
真的吗？
Really?
我为什么该帮你？
What makes you think I should help you?
不 重点不是我
No, it's not about me.
已经不是了
Not anymore.
我有朋友身陷险境 她需要我帮忙
I have a friend in danger, and she needs my help.
有意思
Fascinating.
亚杰 传提示给我 - 好
Hey, Ajay, can you send the prompt, please? Sure, yeah.
好 你确定吗？
Okay. Hey, are you sure?
好像有一架识别者往这边飞来
Because that looks like an actual Recognizer flying towards us.
那是什么东西？
What in God's name is that?
是雅典娜
It's Athena.
她回来了
She's back.
只要狄林杰网络上线 她就会一直来
As long as the Dillinger Network is online, she'll keep coming.
抓到我 她就能得到永恒代码
If she gets me, she gets the Permanence Code.
激光 雅典娜的激光
The laser. Athena's laser!
狄林杰使用一种无线直连协定
The Dillingers run a wireless direct link protocol,
我们用剩下的激光探测 追溯返航路径
so let's use what's left of the laser to ping the network and trace a path home.
一旦连线 就能破坏整个狄林杰网络
Once you have a connection, then you can nuke the whole Dillinger Grid.
那是唯一彻底阻止她的方法
And that's the only way to stop her for good.
伊芙 你在说什么？她就在那里
Eve, what are you talking about? She's right there.
我会尽量牵制她
I'll keep her away for as long as I can.
追踪目标中 伊芙金
Tracking target: Eve Kim.
没错 我应该有问题
You're right. I think there is something wrong with me.
或者 也许你有好的地方
Or maybe there's something right with you.
也许你只是在学习
Well, maybe you're just learning.
我们都应该那么做
That's what we all ought to be doing.
当年科技刚开始萌芽时
Back in the day, when tech was young,
我会想：“我们进展得好快”
I'd think, "Damn, we're moving fast."
进展快 就会抛下一些东西
You move fast, you leave stuff behind.
这世纪出生的人有多少个听过莫札特？
How many people born in this century have even heard of Mozart?
我喜欢莫札特
I like Mozart.
但老实说 我比较喜欢流行尖端
That said, if I'm being honest, I prefer Depeche Mode.
是吗？怎么说？
Really? Why is that?
一个被誉为西方文明史上
I know one is considered the greatest composer
最伟大的作曲家
in the history of Western civilization,
一个是 80 年代的合成流行乐团
the other a synth pop band from the '80s,
但他们的音乐兼具实验性与流行元素
but I find their balance of technological exploration
再加上...
and pop hooks combined with...
combined with, uh...
怎么了？
What's wrong?
我无法用言语形容对流行尖端的喜爱
I-I can't put my love of Depeche Mode into words.
那只是...
It's just a...
什么？
Hmm? A what?
一种感觉
A feeling.
非常好
Very good.
Very good, man.
一艘大如摩天楼的飞船刚进入本市领空
A spacecraft the size of a skyscraper has just entered city airspace.
并前往市区...
and is heading downtown...
你...
You...
是你造成的
You did this.
今晚 军方...
And tonight, as military...
了不起 完全分段的零信任架构
Impressive. Fully segmented zero trust architecture.
可以抵御垂直 横向或混合攻击
Built to be totally impregnable to vertical, lateral or hybrid attacks.
狄林杰网络 连线中断
Dillinger Network: Connection terminated.
可恶 连不上 - 这里也是
Damn it. Can't get a connection, dude. No luck here either.
遭拒
Denied.
疯狂空间
Space Paranoids.
请立即撤离本区域
Please, evacuate the area.
那是什么？找反恐特警组 - 请求支援
What is that thing? -Bring in SWAT! -Requesting backup.
天啊
Oh, my God.
Oh, my God!
来啊 再靠近一点
Come on. A little closer.
伊芙金
Eve Kim.
毒蛇一号呼叫基地 看见敌方
Viper-1 to base. Tally on hostile.
目视确认目标
Confirmed visual ID.
攻击 狐狸二号飞弹已发射
Engaging Fox-2. Missile away.
未命中 飞弹已被拦截
Splash negative. Missile intercepted.
注意 敌方护航战斗机快速逼近
Be advised, enemy fighter escorts inbound and moving fast.
收到 渡鸦一号 评估威胁态势
Copy, Raven-1. Assess and report threat posture.
毒蛇一号 看见多架敌机
Viper-1, tally multiple bandits.
确认对方有敌意
Hostile intent confirmed.
求救... 我被击中了
Mayday. Mayday. I'm hit!
毒蛇一号 弹射逃生
Viper-1. Punching out.
发射
Fire!
各位 各位
Uh, guys? Guys.
天啊 有几百个
Oh, my God. There's hundreds of 'em.
他们在追伊芙
They're going after Eve.
进不了狄林杰服务器就没东西可救了
If we can't access the Dillinger server, there's gonna be nothing left to save.
渡鸦一号呼叫基地 敌机发动攻击
Base, this is Raven-1. Enemy aircraft engaging.
我在防御状态
I'm defensive.
有多架敌机 转向主要目标
Multiple bandits. Redirecting to primary target.
我被击中了 弹射逃生
I'm hit! Punching out.
准备好了吗？
Ready?
希望如此 无法回头了
Hope you are, man, 'cause there's no going back.
恒久
Permanence.
说来好玩
Funny.
我发现它时就是这么叫它
When I found it, that's what I called it.
我现在学聪明了
I know better now.
应该叫短暂代码
Ought to be called the Impermanence Code.
后门通往我的旧实验室
The back door to my old lab.
一次机会
One go-around.
你只有一次
That's all you've got.
一次机会...
One...
就是我要的
is all I want.
我喜欢
Love that!
你不断令我惊奇
You keep surprising me!
那我们就在地面进行
We'll do this from the ground then.
创界网络
The Grid.
费林
Flynn.
抵达转移区所需时间
ETA to transfer zone.
据报上面可能有一个平民
and there are reports that a civilian may be onboard,
代表可能有人遭到挟持
making this a possible hostage scenario.
雅典娜 她一定抓到伊芙了
Athena. She must've gotten Eve.
进入山区
into the mountains.
喂...
Hey, hey, hey!
我们很快就回创界网络
Soon we'll be back on the Grid.
将军 感谢你今晚拨空接受访问
General, thank you for taking the time to speak with us tonight.
艾琳 赛斯
Hey, Erin. Seth.
连接狄林杰网络中
Connecting to Dillinger Network.
连线已建立
Connection established.
停止计时器
Stop the clock.
不会吧 你进去了？
No way. You're in?
我用角落办公室是有原因的
There's a reason why I have the corner office, my man.
嘿
Hey.
你回来了
You came back.
你怎么...
How did you...
姑且说我有朋友帮忙
Let's just say I had a little help from a friend.
等等 狄林杰网络...
Wait, the Dillinger Grid...
亚杰和赛斯...
Ajay and Seth, they...
战神
Ares!
战神 消解错误
Ares, de-resolution error.
你做了什么？
What have you done?
你没时间了 雅典娜
You're out of time, Athena.
而你要没命了
And you're out of lives.
我会杀了你 再回来找她
I'll kill you and come back for her.
她要的是你
It's you she wants.
让她拿到代码就完了
If she gets the code, she can't be stopped.
你曾拥有一切
You had everything.
最先进 最强大的能力 你却轻易放弃
The most advanced, the most powerful, and you gave it away.
为了她？
For her?
快跑
Go!
这是你的末日
This is the end for you.
有效负载准备转移
Payload ready for transfer.
运送中
Shipping it.
狄林杰 执行网络清除 自毁
Dillinger, execute network purge and self-destruct.
传送有效负载
Transmitting payload.
希望伊芙是对的
Let's hope Eve was right.
字幕制作：葫 芦 Q 群：491019388
Subtitles by Hulu QQ Group: 491019388
警告 不明档案传入
Alert. Unknown file incoming.
为了自己追求生命
In pursuit of this life for yourself,
你考虑过这对创界网络的影响吗？
did you once consider what that meant for the Grid?
我们接到命令 它是我们的使命
We were given an order. It is our purpose.
它不是我们的使命
It's not our purpose.
是我们的设定
It's our programming.
我们的使命尚未决定
Our purpose is yet to be determined.
连接狄林杰网络中
Connecting to Dillinger Network.
连线失败
Connection failed.
系统离线
System offline.
结束了
It's over.
无法回头了
And there's no coming back.
不
No.
这次不行
Not this time.
他们成功了
They did it.
天啊
Oh, my...
我遵照我的指令
I followed my directive.
我知道
I know.
现在...
And now...
你的指令是什么？
what is yours?
我不确定
I'm not sure.
狄林杰系统今晚面临严密搜查
Dillinger Systems is under intense scrutiny tonight
外界怀疑它可能涉及
as speculation grows around its potential involvement
使本市陷入动荡的一连串毁灭性攻击
in the series of devastating attacks that have rocked the city.
联邦当局已证实正积极调查
Federal authorities have confirmed
该公司近期的活动
an active investigation into the company's recent activity,
许多事件直接指向执行长朱利安狄林杰
and many are pointing directly at CEO Julian Dillinger.
当局已指派探员讯问执行长与他的母亲
Agents have been deployed to question the CEO as well as his mother,
并联络董事会...
and to locate board members
系统严重故障
Critical system failure.
激光校正中
Laser calibration in progress.
厘清相关情形
who will be questioned on the situation.
此外 本市依然一片混乱
Meanwhile, the city remains in disarray.
急难救护单位不堪负荷
Emergency services are overwhelmed,
有整片区域遭到大规模破坏
while entire neighborhoods are dealing with the wide-scale destruction.
关闭
Shutting down.
重启激光中
Restarting laser.
重启失败
Restart failed.
朱利安狄林杰 我们是警察
Julian Dillinger, this is the police.
你被包围了
We have you surrounded.
开门 高举双手走出来
Open the door and come out with your hands up.
激光系统上线
Laser system online.
上线
Online.
快啊
Come on.
激光校正中
Laser calibration in progress.
转移已反转
Transfer reversed.
破门
Breach!
警察
Police!
待在原地
Stay where you are!
继续监控所有出口
Maintain visuals on all exits.
查理九号 我们在最后指定位置...
Charlie-9, we're at last field location. Last field location.
黄色六号 在前面 快去...
Yellow-6, out front. Let's move. Let's move.
你还好吗？
Are you good?
好像有肋骨断了
Oh, I think I broke a rib.
你还会辞职吗？
You still gonna quit your job?
不 我不会放弃任何东西
No, I'm not gonna quit anything.
很好
Good.
我有一些想法
I have some ideas.
是吗？很好 - 嗯
Oh, yeah? Nice. -Yeah.
这世界需要你 伊芙
Well, the world needs you, Eve.
创界网络需要你
The Grid needs you.
说来奇怪 恒久...
Yeah. It's funny, permanence.
有个智者说它应该叫 “短暂代码”
A wise man once told me it should have been called the "Impermanence Code."
我想那就是生命的特点
I guess that's the thing about life.
没有什么是恒久的
There's nothing quite permanent about it.
没错
No.
确实没有
No, there isn't.
是啊
Yeah.
你要去哪里？
So where are you gonna go?
我有一些想法
I have some ideas.
英克尔在执行长伊芙金领导下
Under the leadership of CEO Eve Kim,
推动产业转型
Encom is transforming industries...
费林不死
Flynn lives on.
以过去难以想像的方式形塑生活
and shaping lives in ways once thought impossible.
由于发现了永恒代码
Thanks to the discovery of the Permanence Code,
该公司取得了革命性的进展
the company has made revolutionary advances
在气候脆弱区域种植作物
growing crops in climate-vulnerable regions,
针对耐药性癌症研发药物
developing drugs for treatment-resistant cancers,
以及加速替代燃料的开发
and accelerating the development of alternative fuels.
英克尔致力于探索数字新领域
Encom is committed to exploring new digital frontiers,
推动科技与生命的融合发展
driving progress at the intersection of technology and life itself
以改善人类的生活品质
to improve the human condition.
事实上 创新始终是英克尔的核心
In fact, innovation has always been at the heart of Encom.
1980 年代 深具远见的凯文费林
In the 1980s, visionary Kevin Flynn
想像一个游戏之外的未来
imagined a future beyond gaming,
大胆跃入数字新领域
a bold leap into new digital frontiers.
如今 那个愿景已经成真
Today, that vision is a reality.
我差点忘了
Oh, I almost forgot.
明信片？谁还用邮寄的？ - 不知道
Postcard? Who sends a postcard? -Don't know.
我没看
Didn't read it.
亲爱的伊芙
Dear Eve,
自从上次见到你
since I last saw you,
我都过着所谓的 “外网络” 生活
I've been living what they call "off-grid."
我故意用双关语
Pun intended.
我在旅行中见到不可思议的事物
In my travels, I've seen incredible things.
尽管奇妙 美丽 我却发觉生活...
Despite its wonder and beauty, I've come to realize that life is...
呃 一言难尽
Well, it's hard to put in a nutshell.
有时我会想百年后我们会在哪里
Some days, I find myself wondering where we'll be a hundred years from now...
神秘伙伴在英克尔有何角色？
What role will my mysterious partner play at Encom?
跟我同类的人如何融入未来
and how others like me might fit into that future.
我觉得可能不只有我有这些疑问
I feel like I might not be alone with these questions.
现在 我想世人还没准备要认识我
For now, I don't think the world is quite ready to meet me,
但我正在认识这个世界
but I am meeting the world.
所以 等那一刻终于来临
And so, when that introduction finally comes,
就像我一个好友说的
as a good friend of mine once said,
“或许未知带来的终究没那么可怕”
"Maybe what emerges from the unknown won't be so scary after all."
半圆顶小屋
Dome Cabin.
期待再相见
Until we meet again,
你的朋友战神
your friend, Ares.
广东绿皇香鸡虎门万达专卖店提供字幕《片名：创：战神》
Green Emperor Fragrant Chicken (Guangdong) Humen Store《title：Tron: Ares》